<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>faan|ross</title>
    <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/</link>
    <description>Recent content on faan|ross</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>| hack the planet</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://athul.github.io/archie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Threat Hunting for Beginners: Hunting Standard Dll-Injected C2 Implants (Practical Course)</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/posts/course01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/posts/course01/</guid>
      <description>NOTE THIS IS CURRENTLY STILL WIP, THE REASON IT&amp;rsquo;S A PUBLIC DRAFT IS LONG AND CONVOLUTED SO JUST TRUST ME. ANYHOO - DO AS YOU WISH. Hello friend, so glad you could make it. This is the first in an ongoing + always-evolving series on threat hunting.
The main thing I want you to know about this course is that we will learn by doing.
(1) We&amp;rsquo;ll start off by creating + configuring our own virtual network, including systems for the victim, attacker, and analyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/about/</guid>
      <description>this site contains original content related to threat hunting, active defense, and deception.
but since you clicked on about i&amp;rsquo;m gonna assume you also want to learn a bit about me, faan ross.
first off, this is not me. this is nathan fielder, but i really like him and really like this gif - so why not start there?
further, since we find ourselves here it should come as no great shock that I love all things cybersecurity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Modes of Threat Hunting</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/posts/three_modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/posts/three_modes/</guid>
      <description>PREFACE This is a short article covering a single foundational concept related to threat hunting. I&amp;rsquo;m publishing it here as a stand-alone post because I would like to reference it in some of my courses without needing to reproduce it in every such instance. Nevertheless, I hope, even here by itself, it might provide some value to you.
INTRODUCTION Threat hunting, by its literal definition, is predicated on a single presumption: we presume a compromise has already occurred, and thus an adversary is established on our network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course 01 Outline</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/outline/</guid>
      <description># Topic 1 Setting Up Your Virtual Environment 1.1 Introduction 1.2 Requirements 1.3 Hosted Hypervisor 1.4 VM Images 1.5 VM 1: Windows 10 aka &amp;ldquo;The Victim&amp;rdquo; 1.5.1 Installation 1.5.2 VMWare Tools 1.5.3 Deep disable MS Defender + Updates 1.5.4 Sysmon 1.5.5 PowerShell ScriptBlock Logging 1.5.6 Install Software 1.5.7 Creating a Template 1.6 VM 2: Kali Linux aka &amp;ldquo;The Attacker&amp;rdquo; 1.7 VM 3: Ubuntu Linux 20.04 aka &amp;ldquo;The Analyst&amp;rdquo; 1.7.1 Installation 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
