<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course01s on faan|ross</title>
    <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Course01s on faan|ross</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>| hack the planet</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outline: Threat Hunting for Beginners: Hunting Standard Dll-Injected C2 Implants</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/outline/</guid>
      <description>Return to course page
# Topic 0 Pre-Course Banter 1 Setting Up Your Virtual Environment 1.1 Introduction 1.2 Requirements 1.3 Hosted Hypervisor 1.4 VM Images 1.5 VM 1: Windows 10 aka &amp;ldquo;The Victim&amp;rdquo; 1.5.1 Installation 1.5.2 VMWare Tools 1.5.3 Deep disable MS Defender + Updates 1.5.4 Sysmon 1.5.5 PowerShell ScriptBlock Logging 1.5.6 Install Software 1.5.7 Creating a Template 1.6 VM 2: Kali Linux aka &amp;ldquo;The Attacker&amp;rdquo; 1.7 VM 3: Ubuntu Linux 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 0: Pre-Course Banter</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/prebanter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/prebanter/</guid>
      <description>| Return to Course Overview | Proceed to Section 1 |
Threat hunting is not typically viewed as an &amp;ldquo;entry-level&amp;rdquo; cybersecurity discipline, probably because it is a layer of abstraction woven from other, more fundamental, layers of abstraction. It is not a house built from bricks, but a neighborhood built from houses.
I have however created this course specifically with the beginner in mind. What that practically entails is that I do my best to not indulge in pedantry while providing sufficient information that allows you to follow along not only with what we are doing, but crucially, why we are doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 1: Setting Up Our Virtual Environment</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/01_settingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/01_settingup/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 0 | Proceed to Section 2 |
Section 1: Setting Up Our Virtual Environment 1.1. Introduction In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll set up the three VMs we&amp;rsquo;ll need for the course - Windows 10 (Victim), Kali Linux (Attacker), and Ubuntu 20.04 (Post-Mortem Analysis). First we&amp;rsquo;ll download the iso images and use them to install the operating systems. Then, depending on the specific VM, we&amp;rsquo;ll perform some configurations as well as install extra software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 2: Performing the Attack</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/02_attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/02_attack/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 1 | Proceed to Section 3 |
2. Performing the Attack 2.1. Introduction Why are we performing the attack ourselves? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t I just do it, export all the requisite artifacts, and share this with you? Why am I making you go through this rigmarole - is it simply that I am cruel?
Nah. The reason is pretty simple - I have a deep sense of conviction that one can only truly &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; defense if you equally &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 3: Live Analysis - Native Windows Tools</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/03_live_native/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/03_live_native/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 2 | Proceed to Section 4 |
3. Live Analysis: Native Windows Tools 3.1. Introduction So our first analysis will be a quick review using standard (native) Windows tools. These tools are a quick way to get a finger on the pulse - they&amp;rsquo;ll give us a broad overview of some important indicators while at the same time being limited in the depth of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 4: Live Analysis - Process Hacker</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/04_live_hacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/04_live_hacker/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 3 | Proceed to Section 5 |
4. Live Analysis: Process Hacker 4.1. Introduction I explained, hopefully in a somewhat convincing manner, why it&amp;rsquo;s good practice for us to learn how to use the native Windows tools to get an initial, high-level read. But of course these tools are also limited in what information they can provide.
So now let&amp;rsquo;s bring out the big guns and learn all we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 5: Post-Mortem Forensics - Memory</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/05_post_memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/05_post_memory/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 4 | Proceed to Section 6 |
5. Post-Mortem Forensics: Memory 5.1. Transferring the Artifacts First thing&amp;rsquo;s first - we need to transfer the artifacts we produced in 2.3.6 over to our Ubuntu analyst VM.
But just as a note: we&amp;rsquo;ll only transfer our memory dump and packet capture. We won&amp;rsquo;t transfer our log files - I&amp;rsquo;ll explain exactly why later.
Ok so there are a number of ways we can transfer our files over, and if you have your own method you prefer please go ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 6: Post-Mortem Forensics - Log Analysis</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/06_post_logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/06_post_logs/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 5 | Proceed to Section 7 |
6. Post-Mortem Forensics: Log Analysis 6.1. Introduction Now typically we might think of logging as belonging more to the realm of the SOC than a threat hunter. That&amp;rsquo;s because, at least in the way that modern logging practices operate, logging is not seen as something directly approachable by a human operator.
What do I mean by this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 7: Post-Mortem Forensics - Traffic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/07_post_traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/07_post_traffic/</guid>
      <description>| Course Overview | Return to Section 6 | Proceed to Section 8 |
Section 7: Post-Mortem Forensics - Traffic Analysis 7.1. Introduction In many respects, the realm of network packets is the ultimate domain for threat hunting. It is the only place where malware cannot hide, especially if it intends to communicate. Thus, even if malicious traffic is buried under an avalanche of legitimate traffic, one thing is for sure: the malware&amp;rsquo;s communication is always present, somewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 8: Course Review</title>
      <link>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/08_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://athul.github.io/archie/course01/08_review/</guid>
      <description>| Return to Course Overview |
first thing create comparison image
x
| Return to Course Overview |</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
